ANKUR SINGH

DevOps SDE - II





TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JAVA, Groovy

Tools: GitLab, Jenkins, GoCD, Ansible, Consul, Nomad, NEXUS, JIRA, Vault, Terraform.

Knowledge: AWS Cloud, Docker, Kubernetes, Blockchain.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Became Gitlab Certified Associate (April 2021)
- Won Smart India Hackathon 2020 as a technical mentor for MS450 (Aug 2020)

EXTRAPROFESSIONALS

- Facilitator for technical workshops & seminars
- Mentor for hackathons and software projects

EDUCATION

BACHELORS OF ENGINEERING

University of Mumbai | I.T.

June 2015 - May 2019 | CGPA:8.2

- Organised events along with ACM committee.
- Delivered hands-on technical workshops.

ABOUT ME

My passion for software development and the keen interest to understand the operational processes in a software development life cycle were totally fulfilled as I entered in the professional world as a DevOps engineer. Since I started my journey for bachelors degree, I have worked on development of Android Application & Blockchain based applications and currently I am responsible for implementation of DevOps practices & reduce manual overheads by automating processes.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

ZYCUS Infotech Pvt. Ltd. | Jul 2019 - Mar 2022

- Implemented automations to integrate devops tool stack for end-to-end & no manual processes.
- Handling frequent stable releases of around 90+ products on staging & production environments.
- Ensuring maximum uptime of products to meet SLAs and debugging production issues

DEVOPS SDE - II

HERE Solutions | Apr 2022 - Present

 Maintaining huge dev & production kubernetes clusters with rolling upgrades, bug fixes and feature releases

PROJECTS

GitLabCI Adoption

- Designed a standard process to automate setup/installation of necessary components for using GitlabCI with docker based runners.
- Reduced manual efforts & configuration mismatch issues by 90% with automated validation & merging of configurations on commit.

Zero Downtime CICD Implementation

- Led, designed and implemented workflow to ensure upgrades of products without downtime and minimal manual intervention.
- Reduced manual efforts and CICD timeframe by 75% with quicker dev-to-production workflows.